So in the last lesson we talked about how we can invite friends to do things with us in a very natural
所以上一课我们讲了如何邀请朋友和我们一起很自然地做事
and informal way.
和非正式的方式。
Like most situations but in this video I want to talk about how we talk about the differences between
像大多数情况一样，但在这个视频中，我想谈谈我们如何谈论
things or the similarities between things differences.
事物的相似之处或事物之间的差异。
I think you probably know this word and similarities.
我想你可能知道这个词和相似之处。
What is kind of the same or almost the same and what is very different.
什么是相同或几乎相同的，什么是非常不同的。
OK now we're going to talk about what we call comparatives how we compare things this thing and this
好的，现在我们将讨论我们所说的比较我们如何比较事物 this 和 this
thing.
事物。
And we can compare all kinds of things we can compare objects actually physical things or we can compare
我们可以比较各种事物，我们可以比较物体实际上是物理事物，或者我们可以比较
ideas we can compare things in time we can compare amounts of things.
我们可以及时比较事物的想法 我们可以比较事物的数量。
There are all sorts of things that we need to compare in everyday life.
在日常生活中，我们需要比较各种事物。
So if you know how to do this and you can do it very easily and naturally then you're able to very specifically
因此，如果您知道如何做到这一点，并且可以非常轻松自然地做到这一点，那么您就可以非常具体
explain for example.
举例说明。
No I don't want that one.
不，我不想要那个。
I want that one.
我想要那个。
Which one.
哪一个。
The one which is a little bit more blah blah blah.
那个有点多废话。
So we're going to learn that in today's lesson.
所以我们将在今天的课程中学习这一点。
So let's just get started with some of the basics.
因此，让我们从一些基础知识开始吧。
You probably have said and have heard people say bigger than smaller then or more interesting then less
您可能已经说过并且听说过人们说大于小于小于或更有趣然后小于
interesting then.
那么有趣。
So why is it that sometimes we use her and sometimes we use more or less.
那么为什么有时我们使用她，有时我们或多或少地使用。
So I want to go through some examples so that this is clear and then we'll then we'll go on and do some
所以我想通过一些例子来说明这一点，然后我们会继续做一些
more complicated some more detailed comparisons.
更复杂一些更详细的比较。
But first we have to start with the basics.
但首先我们必须从基础开始。
So why is it that we might say this apple is more is the basic structure delicious than that to Apple.
那么为什么我们可以说这个苹果比苹果的基本结构更美味。
OK.
好的。
This apple is more delicious than that apple.
这个苹果比那个苹果好吃。
And over here we might say over here we might say this is easier.
在这里我们可能会说在这里我们可能会说这更容易。
You are right.
你说的对。
This is easier than I thought it would be.
这比我想象的要容易。
OK.
好的。
So here we have two.
所以这里我们有两个。
One uses E R and one is using more and then this one is also using then they all use then.
一个使用 E R，一个使用更多，然后这个也使用，然后他们都使用。
Well at least when we're talking about the differences between things one and another and how they're
好吧，至少当我们谈论事物之间的差异以及它们之间的差异时
different it's pretty simple actually.
不同其实很简单。
Why this one E R is usually when there are one or two syllables.
为什么这个 E R 通常是在一两个音节的时候。
Now if you don't know a syllable a syllable is a beat in a word.
现在，如果你不知道一个音节，一个音节就是一个单词的节拍。
So let's look at the word just very quickly.
所以让我们很快地看一下这个词。
Let's work.
开始干活。
Look at the word basketball.
看看篮球这个词。
If I look at the word basketball it's very difficult to tell how many syllables are or beats are in
如果我看篮球这个词，很难说出有多少音节或节拍
the word.
这个单词。
But if we actually say it out loud we can hear the number of bump bump bump beats in the word basketball.
但是，如果我们真的大声说出来，我们可以听到篮球这个词中颠簸颠簸的次数。
Now that's easy for me to hear.
现在这对我来说很容易听到。
But sometimes when you're learning English it can be a little bit difficult to hear how many that is.
但有时当你学习英语时，可能有点难以听清它是多少。
My name is Luke.
我叫卢克。
How many syllables does my name have.
我的名字有多少个音节。
One or two.
一个或两个。
Actually it's one but to make sure you can hear it correctly say the word with your mouth closed.
实际上它是一个，但要确保你能听到它闭着嘴正确说出这个词。
Luke hmm hmm hmm hmm.
卢克嗯嗯嗯嗯。
I'm saying it but my mouth is closed.
我这么说，但我的嘴是闭着的。
There's only one beat.
只有一拍。
OK.
好的。
Basketball.
篮球。
Hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm.
嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯嗯。
Three syllables.
三个音节。
So when you're looking at how many syllables.
因此，当您查看有多少个音节时。
Don't look at.
别看。
Don't look at the letters in the word because you can have a long word with not many syllables and a
做不要看单词中的字母，因为你可以有一个音节不多的长单词和一个
short word with many syllables.
多音节的短词。
It's more about the sound.
更多的是关于声音。
And to get a feeling for it close your mouth and then you can hear it.
为了感受它，闭上你的嘴，然后你就能听到它。
What's the rule then why are we talking about syllables.
有什么规则那么我们为什么要谈论音节。
Well generally if you have one or two syllables then you're going to use her for example faster easier.
好吧，一般来说，如果你有一个或两个音节，那么你会更快更容易地使用她。
All right.
好的。
Easy easy.
慢慢来。
Two syllables fast fast.
两个音节快快。
Bigger smaller.
更大更小。
And then if you have three syllables or more like delicious How many syllables are in the word delicious
然后如果你有三个音节或更多像美味一样的单词有多少个音节
delicious delicious.
好吃好吃。
Three syllables.
三个音节。
OK so more delicious.
好的，这样更好吃。
That's got all of them there.
他们都在那里。
Don't worry then more delicious then.
不用担心然后更好吃。
OK.
好的。
More interesting then more beautiful then more appealing then.
更有趣然后更美丽然后更吸引人。
OK so three or more syllables.
好的，三个或更多音节。
Now there are some times when you'll see a two syllable word also using more then.
现在有时你会看到一个两个音节的单词也使用 more then。
So for example if you say funny you say funnier funnier he is funnier than him.
因此，例如，如果您说有趣，您会说更有趣，他比他更有趣。
Tom is funnier than Jerry.
汤姆比杰瑞有趣。
That's.
那是。
That's right.
这是正确的。
That's totally correct.
这是完全正确的。
But also you'll see Tom is more funny than Jerry and that is correct as well.
但你也会看到汤姆比杰瑞更有趣，这也是正确的。
So for two syllable words I would say generally speaking use her.
所以对于两个音节的词，我会说一般来说使用她。
But there are some cases where more is much more common.
但在某些情况下，更多更常见。
And it's just because of the way that language is in language you never really know why something is
只是因为语言在语言中的方式，你永远不知道为什么会这样
more popular than another why why this word is more common than this word or this way of saying it is
比另一个更受欢迎 为什么这个词比这个词或这种说法更常见
more common.
比较普遍;普遍上。
So you really just have to pay attention and look out for cases where two syllable adjectives use more
所以你真的只需要注意并注意两个音节形容词使用更多的情况
instead of her.
而不是她。
Here's a perfect example.
这是一个完美的例子。
More more common then you really don't see.
比你真正看不到的更常见。
Commoner then more common that is pretty much the only way it's done.
Commoner then more common 这几乎是唯一的方法。
So you have to look out for these when it comes to the two syllable words for the one syllable words
所以你必须注意这些当涉及到一个音节词的两个音节词时
and the three syllable words pretty much always you can say this is E R and this is more or less in
这三个音节词几乎总是你可以说这是 E R 这或多或少在
fact.
事实。
Same rule but for the two syllable ones you really have to pay attention again as a general rule.
相同的规则，但对于两个音节的规则，你真的必须再次注意作为一般规则。
Go for e r.
去吧。
Sometimes it depends on the sound.
有时这取决于声音。
For example the word tender already has e r at the end.
例如，tender 这个词的末尾已经有 e r。
So if you say tender tenderer tender sounds a bit strange right.
所以如果你说嫩嫩嫩的听起来有点奇怪吧。
So it will be more common to say more tender just because of the earth sound of the adjective Wicked
因此，仅仅因为形容词 Wicked 的地音而说更温柔会更常见
is also another good example.
也是另一个很好的例子。
Wicked means someone is really bad really bad or cruel to others right.
邪恶的意思是某人真的很糟糕，真的很糟糕或对别人很残忍。
Very wicked.
非常邪恶。
Actually it has a more modern meaning as well.
实际上，它也具有更现代的含义。
Something is really cool people say Oh man that's wicked but I don't know if that's popular anymore
有些东西真的很酷，人们说哦，伙计，这很邪恶，但我不知道这是否流行了
anyway.
反正。
Wicked would be one where you would say more wicked then just because it sounds a little bit weird to
Wicked 将是一个你会说更 wicked 的地方，因为这听起来有点奇怪
say wicked or wicked or it's kind of hard to say so sometimes because it's hard to say or because it
说 wicked 或 wicked 或者有时很难这么说，因为很难说，或者因为它
sounds weird people prefer more even though it's a two syllable word.
听起来很奇怪，人们更喜欢它，即使它是一个两个音节的词。